LUKE SHAFER

FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

614 - 585 - 3382 hello@lukeshafer.com Columbus, Ohio

SKILLS

Languages

- TypeScript JavaScript
- CSS (& preprocessors)
- Python
- HTML

Libraries & Frameworks

- React
- Svelte
- SvelteKit
- Strapi
- NextJS
- Astro

Practices

- Accessibility (A11y)
- Semantic HTML
- Componentization
- Scalable Design

Soft Skills

- Project management
- Team communication
- Customer service

PROFILE

Hi! I'm a web developer with over 5 years of professional experience, focused on accessible, modern, and concise design. I'm experienced in modern frontend web technologies, including React and Svelte, and can quickly learn any stack or technology introduced to me.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer

Columbus, Ohio | 2022-Present

I started Luke Shafer Web Design to help local small businesses with their web development needs. I use modern frameworks like SvelteKit and Astro to build custom, flexible, and accessible sites for my clients.

Implementation Specialist, TrueCommerce

Columbus, OH | 2021-Present

Designed EDI software integrations using scripting in accordance with customer business requirements, and provided personable customer service.

Online Coding Instructor, CodeWizardsHQ

Remote | 2020-2021

Led curriculum-based courses with students in grades 3-12, teaching coding concepts from scratch. I taught classes in Python, Javascript, and Scratch.

PROJECTS

Fridge Magnets

magnets.dev.lukeshafer.com | github.com/lukeshafer/fridge-magnets

Custom online multiplayer word game, and an online implementation of the card game <u>Ransom Notes</u>. Built with <u>colyseus.io</u> for the game server, and SvelteKit for the front-end game UI, using TypeScript to power the full stack.

Personal Portfolio

lukeshafer.com | github.com/lukeshafer/lukeshafer.com

My personal portfolio and a place for prospective clients or employers to view my work. Statically generated in SvelteKit and hosted on CloudFlare Pages.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's, Computer Science, 2018

University of Cincinnati, Cincinnati, Ohio

